Hello everyone, welcome to the subject Cybersecurity.
As you could see here, the subject code is 48730 for undergraduate and 32548 for the
postgraduate students.
So in the next few minutes, I'm going to introduce this subject in terms of what is important
in this subject, what we're going to study and why Cybersecurity has got such a prominent
place in the internet world.
Myself is Prayadashinanda from School of Electrical and Data Engineering within the Faculty of
Engineering and IT.
Now as you know, in the last few decades, the use of internet has been significant and when
there have been a lot of businesses who have transitioned from the standalone business
operation to internet-based, cloud-based, IoT-based operations, there are a lot of applications
which are also part of the internet.
So when we say cyber, so cyber is a term where everything is connected to the internet and
securing those, everything is of utmost importance.
So if you look at the term cyber security, so it actually evolved from various terminologies
in the past.
For example, it started with the computer security.
Then when computers were interconnected, it became network security.
Then when information, massive amount of information were actually transmitted across the devices
in the network or in the internet, it became information security and as I said, application
security, business continuity, planning and so on.
So with all these things, we need to ensure that the operations, what we are doing over
the internet or over the cyber, they're actually protected.
So protection of software, hardware and various resources is of utmost importance.
And if you look at the data, like how cyber security has gained significant attention by
the industries, by businesses, by individuals, the Gardener report itself says by 2022, the
cyber security expenditure or the budget will be something around one trillion US dollar.
And that exactly tells you the importance of cyber security.
The most important thing in the cyber security while we're doing all this security aspect
for protecting the device, protecting the application, protecting the business, protecting
the personal information, because the attackers are getting more and more active in the last
few decades.
They are using various kinds of things such as various methodologies, various tools, various
advanced mechanisms to get your information, to violate the cyber space.
So essentially, when you say the attackers, the attackers basically targeting everything
which are connected to the internet and we have a lot of stories in the past few years.
So we start our discussion in this subject, going through say hackers, malware, ransomware,
we'll also go through many case studies, how actually over the last few years the importance
of cyber security is so prominent.
And always remember the attackers always deliberately attack for financial or some kind of personal
motives.
So what we're actually going to learn in this particular subject is understanding those
attacks, understanding the technological aspect of the attacks, understanding the management
aspect of the attacks and of course the socio economical aspect of the attack.
So where we say the policy, the governance and all those things will come into picture.
So the security elements within the cyber security that is very fast, it starts from
the cyber crime to cyber harassment to cyber bullying, cyber surveillance, foreign seeks
and so many areas where actually these storms have been applied.
So as I mentioned, we have to be very careful when we are actually participating in the
internet internet era.
So the next question happens, how cyber security is different from other security.
Now I just now told you that there are various storms which are associated with cyber security
and cyber security basically right now is an umbrella which covers all those other security
aspects including the information security, network security, internet security and so
on.
So protecting the hardware, protecting the software, protecting the application, protecting the
user is the most important aspect what we are going to learn in this introductory level
cyber security subject.
As you know, the internet has transformed itself in a massive way like no other technology.
So if you look at the history of the internet like 30, 40 years back, so it was a platform
which was basically intended to communicate with each other.
When I said communicate, nobody ever thought at that point of time, the voice video and
every kind of communication right.
And as the technology progressed, a lot of things happened on the internet and that's
why we see ourselves being part of the internet and being an integral part of the internet
sharing information, sharing videos, sharing charts, sharing lectures, even going to the
extent of real-time application like operating on a patient monitoring and being getting
advice from the doctor over the internet which is in real time.
When all these things are happening on the internet, the bad guys are bad guys.
So basically they always try to interfere in your business and in this case the business
is information.
So if you see in the past few years there have been many documents which outlines how cyber
security is important.
And every day you find maybe hundreds or sometimes thousands of security breaches which are happening
around the world across the businesses.
It's not actually targeted to individual or specific business but across the businesses.
So it is very important to have a proper understanding what those security terms involved with cyber
security means.
So if you see here, I mean one of the things is internet of things, giving you an example
and similarly other objects can be also can play input and role on the cyberspace.
So the vast exponential increase in terms of huge of internet of things objects or which
are basically the small tiny sensor devices gives you an example of how much data those
devices are actually generating.
And those data needs to be secured from every angle.
It should be private, it should be, the internet should be protected, the authenticity, who
is actually going to use the internet or the devices that should be protected so that they
can be applied to various application areas and the application area can start from the
healthcare to automotive, you know, intelligent transport system to with elaborate applications
like the freeze, the toaster, like the tea kettle, they're all connected to the internet
nowadays.
And many people they actually connect all these devices to get some fun out of that connectivity.
Okay, so essentially the huge growth of IoT has also generated a lot of data in the cyberspace.
So and the most important thing is that when we actually connect to the internet or the
cyberspace, very few people actually think about the security aspect, they simply get
a connection and then get connected, okay.
And that is exactly the breeding ground for the cyber attackers, how they can learn all
those information and learns the attack.
So the main importance or the main objectives of cyber security is to keep the bad guys
out at the same time, protect your information resources.
And that covers everything around like how we can protect against unauthorized users,
how we can protect against the man in the middle attack, how we can protect against preserving
the data in its original form, okay.
So encryption, decryption, those are the terms which are actually part of the security measures
what one can consider.
And these are the important technology area.
So if you look at the look in the last few years, how the applications have been emerging
and how the applications are being there in the cyberspace.
So you'll see the critical infrastructure, mobile computing, social networking, which
is very widely being used by people, by businesses, like Twitter, the LinkedIn, Facebook, and
there are hundreds of such attacks which are happening in these platforms and we'll have
to be careful about that.
Cloud computing, trusted infrastructure, like how we use the certificates and all, big
data, internet of things.
The most important thing what we need to understand and what we will be studying in this subject
is how to protect ourselves.
The moment you actually connect to the internet or the cyberspace, your data, your 100% your
data is being exposed.
Whether it is protected and if it is protected up to what extent is the thing what you should
consider before you actually connect.
So there is a say with sales, think before you connect, because if you don't think before
you connect to the cyber infrastructure or cyberspace, you are essentially exposing yourself
to the attacks and that's why all these security measures are in place, whether it is at the
user name or whether in the network site or in the server site or in the cloud, if you
are part of the cloud because most of the business is now they are actually operating
on the cloud.
There are various standards and standard bodies, we also have a focus on those standard
bodies and for example the National Institute of Standards and Technology need which is
a US standardization body and they are basically very active in terms of you know, satisfying
or standardizing the security documents.
In this society, everything starting from the software to hardware to protocol, everything
actually they actually are very active in this particular space.
International telecommunication union mainly governing the telecommunication aspect, telecommunication
protocol but then in an integrated network, your telecommunication is also part of the
cyberspace.
So there are also a lot of standardization documents you will find.
International standardization or international organization for standardization is basically
the one which was very actively involved and is being involved in the computer network.
For example OSI, several are architecture, how the network was evolved and so on.
In Australia we have the Australian Signal Directorate which is AST, they also produce
a lot of documents based on their observation on how the cyber security attacks or cyber
attacks are actually happening.
So I would expect you all to have a quick look at all these standardization body and
to get an idea about how they work.
So there are a lot of things happening in the cyberspace, starting from cyber warfare
to terrorism, at national level, at international level, cyber hooliganism, fake news, now a
lot of research right now on the fake news, how to detect the fake news, how do is because
anybody can now type any word and can find some kind of resources from the Google.
But then how through are those news, whether they are fake or they are authentic.
That is very important and that is a big area in the cyberspace.
Privacy, you know you are seeing a lot of documents, a lot of information every day, how the privacy
of the user are being attacked, taking example of Facebook data, Google data, my master card
data, there are a lot of privacy, policy, things that also happen.
Privacy related things are happening.
So the challenge is with all these odds when we have a steady and significant increase
in technology, we have a lot of policies being adapted or being developed by the organization.
Law and enforcement authority, they are actually looking for how to make those information
and extract those information from the cyberspace to prove some kind of quote of law.
When all these challenges are there, the most important thing is how do we actually protect
ourselves as well as the businesses.
So the main essence of cyber security starts with three principles or three terms, one
is called confidentiality, nobody can see your information.
So if it is between Bob and Jackie, so only Bob and Jackie know what they have to see
from each other.
Confidentity, integrity, somebody can sniff into the information what you are sending
at the cyberspace or in the internet and can change.
Say for example, you have a stock broker and you are asking the stock broker to and you
are using a shared channel, secure channel to talk to your stock broker to buy 20 shares.
Now the man in the middle, somebody actually listening to the channel and changes from
20 shares to 2000 shares.
So that is called integrity violation.
The information is being changed, availability, whenever you want the information, what the
secured information, what you want to obtain should be available, particularly in relation
to when you are connecting to your bank, you should get your information securely.
That is availability.
Your information should be available when you want and as a legitimate authentic user.
So how you are going to focus in this subject will start with some kind of, you know, because
the cyber security actually originated from network security.
So we will be actually understanding how those network systems are attacked going through
the security aspects of your TCP IP protocol or HTTP protocol or OSI protocol level and
so on.
So going from there, most of the attacks actually are happening through the browser, right, at
the application level and how we protect the browsers, all the functionalities of the
browsers.
Many people, they don't know how to set the browser to its proper configuration, setting
up all the security features.
So we will also talk about secure protocols such as, you know, secure online transactions,
your shopping, making use of the underlying protocol, which is called SSH or TSL or SSL
or VPN, okay.
Then we will be talking about detection system, which are involved with integer detection
system, integer prevention system, how we monitor the traffic and the behavior of the
user intelligently, going from there, we will have some discussion on the policy aspect
of cyber security, which is mainly to be given by two guest lectures in this semester.
And they will be talking about the security risk, security governance, security, you know,
threat intelligence, cyber policy and so on.
So what we actually expect in this subject for you to be engaged with is some kind of,
you know, interactive learning, student input and case studies and we'll be actually
I'll be taking every week the lecture and then we'll have time to discuss about what
we actually covered in the lecture as well as getting your question and answering your
questions.
We'll have some practical aspects, so we'll be using virtual environment to learn few
of the attacks and how to protect against the attacks.
In cyberspace, one thing is very clear, you cannot actually play on the light traffic.
So you have to test it using some kind of simulation tools, software tools or some kind
of, you know, offline checking, okay.
So that is how actually this subject is being organized.
So we have some other subjects, which are also follow which follows this subject, basically
this subject is a prerequisite all these subjects, for example, 4104200, so which is mainly on
cryptography.
Even if in this subject, we will touch some of the cryptographic techniques, but we will
not go that depth into the cryptography.
So this subject 41900 and 420000, so they actually cover every aspect of the photograph.
Network security appearances, so which is a Cisco subject, and that will focus on, you
know, how to implement the security standards, security policies, security protocols, making
use of some kind of, you know, Cisco equipments.
Digital foreign says, as I told you just a couple of minutes back, that is a specialized
area of cyber security and very much integrated within the cyber space, because everybody
wants to investigate what information is that important to find the clue for a case.
So that is how the digital foreign six is also getting momentum with the cyber security.
IoT security, that is another subject which we offer, 42037, that talks about how to
secure the IoT devices, starting from a device level to protocol level to a system level
and so on.
Okay, so you will find a number of subjects which are being part of or which are actually
successor of this cyber security subject.
So that's why this subject is an introductory level subject which will expose you into various
aspect, a variety of aspect in the cyber space.
As you know, all the sources related to this subject will be maintained in the canvas.
Lectures will be conducted every week using the zoom session and the lecture will be
recorded as well as the discussion after the lecture will be recorded and that will be
basically posted once the lecture is finished.
The lab and tutorials, most of the labs and tutorials this semester will be first of
this, particularly for the undergraduate students, for the postgraduate students, those
who are absorbed will be conducting online.
All assessments related to this subject will be conducted online.
So as a result of that, so I would advise you to check your canvas site regularly and
also the emails and notifications which will be going from me as well as from your lab
tutors.
So that is how basically we will explore a lot of things in this subject.
We will get to know what is, what are the different protocols, what are the mechanisms,
how actually we implement the cyber defense strategy.
The objective of this subject is not to make you a hacker very clearly, I am telling you,
but you understand what is involved in hacking.
You do not ask you to be a hacker, but we want you to understand how actually to defend
the system against the hackers.
Thank you very much, get involved in this subject, both in attending the lectures, Agilage, understanding
the lab aspects by implementing and instructions will be given to you for that and make this
subject interesting.
Thank you very much and hope to see you next week in our regular first week lecture.
Thank you.